We're fortunate to have clear skies
Katagiri High School Sports Day
and perfect weather for sports day.
Please practice good sportsmanship
and enjoy this day to the fullest.
Thank you, sir.
And now, the pledge of fair play.
Gloom
We, the students of Katagiri High School,
The class president's looking a little blue.
will now demonstrate the results
of all our training.
Despite his red hair.
It's quite a contrast.
The president actually came to school.
Good thing it's so cool today, huh?
Lots of people are in long sleeves.
Oh, you're right.
Sengoku was saying, "Miyamura-kun's
actually going to try?! That traitor!"
Huh?
I never had a reason to try hard before.
Honestly, the whole thing bored me.
But this year, I've got to beat you.
And now, Katagiri High School sports day...
has officially begun!
Sports Day
Katagiri High School Sports Day
With that, the east and west teams
are looking evenly matched!
I'll bet the second-year girls'
hurdle race had everyone sweating!
Wouldn't you agree, Nakamine-sensei?
It was incredible.
There you have it!
Well done, second-years!
West
Miyamura • Ishikawa • Kawano • Ayasaki • Yanagi
Do the third-years run the hurdles next?
Yep.
Let's go, Sakura.
Just make sure not to get hurt, Remi.
Sure!
Sengoku-san, let's do
the three-legged race together!
East
Hori • Sengoku • Iura • Yoshikawa
I don't have a partner yet.
Sengoku, do topple-the-pole.
They need another boy.
I'd rather be a shellfish...
Next up is the third-year
girls' hurdle race.
Well, I'll see you later!
Good luck, Hori!
Flying high to the east sky!
I guess we're in the same race.
I bet you're really fast.
No, not really.
Yeah, right. Like I believe that.
I shall mow down any who stand in my way.
Good luck!
You can do it!
Do it!
Do it, west team!
Hori-san, Miyamura-kun is cheering for me!
I think he's cheering for
all of Team West, Ayasaki-san.
Next heat, line up.
I'll work hard to impress Miyamura-kun.
I really don't think he
meant you in particular...
On your marks!
If I win, then Miyamura-kun belongs to me,
Kyon-Kyon.
Kyon... Huh?!
Ready...
Hey!
Ayasaki's fast!
Is she the dark horse?
West's Ayasaki-san is leading heat 5!
Uh-oh, that's gonna hurt!
And it'll cost her time!
That sounded painful.
I think she kicked it on purpose.
Whoa...
Ayasaki-san had to go mess with my head.
Damn it!
Team East seems to be trailing behind!
I know that, damn it!
That last girl on the east team
is looking really intense.
Yeah, she's in our class.
Her boyfriend
East takes first! And west takes second!
And after I told Miyamura not to slack...
I suck.
Hori-san, don't give up!
You're not supposed
to cheer for the other team!
Finish strong, Team East!
Damn, she's fast!
East has suddenly picked up speed!
Kyon-Kyon!
Enough with the "Kyon-Kyon" stuff.
You and Miyamura-kun are so in love,
I couldn't bear to steal him from you.
This little...
Just kidding! I've already got Sengoku-kun.
It's so cute that you get flustered so easily.
H-Hey!
H-Hori-san, there you are.
Katagiri High School ~ Sports Day
Sorry, were you discussing something?
We're done, so I'll be on my way.
I'll even take this for you.
Ah, thanks.
How's your leg?
That was quite a hurdle race.
I came in last.
You looked so good in practice.
How come you stalled out?
Because of you!
Scoreboard
East
West
S-So why'd you speed up at the end?
That was because of you, too!
That's not fair!
The next heat is starting,
so I'm going back.
You should, too.
O-Okay.
And one more thing!
Thanks for cheering for me.
It made me happy.
Sure...
Check it out, Miyamura.
Sawada-san's on our team.
Can she even pull the tug-of-war rope?
Swish
Hori-senpai!
Hori going back
to her team's tent
Watch me compete!
Sawada-san's on the other team, right?
I think so.
You can do it, Sawada!
Go for it, Sawada-san!
Snub
What the?
Glance
Grin
I thought maybe I was cheering too loud.
Everyone loves having
someone root for them.
Even you, right?
I don't think I've ever really cheered for
anyone or vice versa at sports day before.
At least cheer more for your team
than our opponents, okay?
It was just the heat of the moment...
Sorry.
Make sure you cheer for me
on the obstacle course.
Drown out the other team, will ya?
West, Fighting Fierce!
Right.
Disappointed
Hori-senpai, we lost.
D-Don't let it get you down. We had
a lot of athletes on the east team side.
I wanted you to see me win!
This is the east team area, you know.
Ishikawa-kun's up next!
Let's give a great cheer.
R-Right.
Iura, you'd better win!
INTENSE
Get first! You hear? First!
Peaceful
Good luck, boys!
Ishikawa— Y-You can do it!
West
Pleasant
East
THUNDEROUS
I wish I were on Team West.
If I lose, my team might kill me.
Where's Sengoku?
He said he's only doing
the events that everyone has to.
On your marks!
Ready...
The boys' obstacle course is underway!
First up is the balance beam!
East and west are neck and neck!
Neither is giving up the lead!
I—
Ishikawa-kun, keep it up!
Ishi—
Ishikawa-kun, what are you doing?!
All together...
Go for it, Ishikawa-kun!
Again! Ready, and...
Go, Ishikawa!
Must be nice to have
the girls cheering for you.
Go, Ishikawa-kun!
Except there's one
high-pitched guy in there, too.
So you're finally...
able to speak up.
Which team will prevail?!
You can do it!
So you tied?
"Well, that must mean that Iura really
went for it," or so Yoshikawa-san said.
You have my praise as well.
Sparkle
Thanks.
Where are the girls?
Getting ready for the cheer
competition coming up next.
Now for the event the boys have been
waiting for, the cheer competition!
First up are the east third-year girls!
Come on, everyone!
Say!
E!
A!
S!
T!
The great-east team!
I just love Senpai!
Disappointed
She's the best!
I've never seen a cheer like this!
Neither have I.
How does her boyfriend feel about it?
Yeah, he's glazed over.
Figured as much.
Fear not, Team West!
Ready? Okay!
Okay!
Go, go, west!
Win, win, west!
We've got this!
Let's go, Team West!
East won over the girls,
and west won over the guys.
Do you think Remi was a little too cute?
Are you listening, Sengoku-san?
Right, right, left, and up!
Now punch up and to the left!
The strong-west team!
I did it!
Good work on the third-year cheer!
Man, that was hot!
Good work!
Hori-san, you did great!
Thanks!
Yoshikawa-san.
Nice job, Kono-san!
The west team looked great!
Y-You mean it?
Thank you.
For helping me practice.
I didn't get to properly thank you.
I-It's a bit late now, but...
You're so serious, Kono-san.
Not really...
Maybe Ishikawa-kun noticed me a little.
West
Sadness...
You knew what was coming.
I just really wanted to see her
in a cheerleading outfit.
Disappointment
Miyamura-kun, can I borrow you for a minute?
West, fighting fierce!
Do you need me for something?
Yes, one of the boys is out with a cold.
Could you please take his place?
You aren't in any individual events, right?
No, but...
A-Are you sure you want me?
I'm asking you, so of course!
Oh, of course.
I'll be right there.
Thanks!
You'll do great.
Miyamura came in third.
What a loser.
Someone more athletic should
have entered all the events.
It made me happy.
You'll do great.
Everyone loves having
someone root for them.
Sports day is actually kind of...
Flying high to the east sky!
Next is the scavenger hunt,
our only coed event!
Open an envelope, find what's written
inside, and bring it to the finish line!
Glasses! Anyone wearing glasses?!
Any girls with ponytails?!
I'll be the first to the finish line!
That's great. I can help you get
to the finish line in life, too.
Hmm?
Someone suspicious
Say, Yoshikawa,
what were you supposed to find?
Th-The youngest teacher.
Oh?
East has reached the finish line!
Yuki finished first.
I need to get going!
I'll finish first, too!
Sorry!
I'll get a different one!
No, you can have it!
Huh? Hori-san?
Miyamura?!
What are you doing here?!
Well, someone was absent,
so I got asked to fill in.
Hori, hurry up!
Crap, I'm falling behind!
Ah...
Flustered
Jeez, what is Miyamura-kun doing?
Both he and Hori-san seem surprised.
Book it, Miyamura!
Keep it up, Kyo-chan...
What're you doing over here, Sengoku?
It was a close call.
East team
They were looking for a sub
and would have entered me,
but I slipped away!
Y-You seem invigorated.
Hey... Wait! What is this?!
C-Could it be that east and
west drew the same thing?!
How does that happen?!
I need him, Miyamura!
I do, too!
Hold on! You're gonna pop out my shoulders!
H-Hang in there!
Hang in there, Sengoku-kun.
You don't need to cheer for me!
No!
The final two participants
have crossed the finish line...
at the same time!
The both seem to have brought
the student council president.
Why'd you have to pick me?
What did you have on your slips?
A skinny boy
Student council president
I understand Kyo-chan.
But you, Miyamura-kun!
There are plenty of other skinny guys!
I thought I should find the skinniest one...
You traitor!
Scoreboard
East
West
The third-year boys' mock cavalry
battle is starting soon!
Announcer
All competitors, please get ready.
You'll be the rider, obviously.
Is it my weight again?
Why is it always about that?!
You'd snap in half
if you were on the bottom.
We're not branches.
If we're doing this,
Sengoku-san, let's win it!
Sure.
Visibly
different
temperatures
Yay, yay!
Yay, yay.
Gimme a "Yeah!", Sengoku-san.
Okay, we're going for Sengoku first.
Yeah!
Got it.
Yanagi-kun's on top, too.
Hey, looking good!
Thanks!
All the riders are the least
competitive people here.
Upsy-daisy!
I'm actually starting to enjoy this.
Really?!
Finally?
The view from up here is great.
Sengoku-san is fancying
himself a general of sorts!
Sengoku looks like he's raring to go.
Time to get to it, guys!
Right.
Sengoku! You'd better score a point!
Go, go!
Hori's cheering for Sengoku.
Of course. She's on his team.
But doesn't that tick you off?
So, what's our strategy?
Sengoku's a clever one.
Then how about this?
Are we supposed to cheer for the rider?
They're all working hard, but the guy
on top has the most important role.
Detail-oriented
I see. The mock cavalry battle
is pretty complex.
Miyamura-kun!
Good luck, Miyamura-kun!
Do your best!
Why are they only calling Miyamura's name?
Sengoku-san, Ayasaki-san
is cheering for Miyamura!
Doesn't that tick you off?!
We're on different teams,
so of course she is.
What are you getting at, Iura-kun?
I'm sorry.
Visibly
different
temperatures
Okay, teams, to your starting positions!
Who will stand in the winner's circle?!
Ready...
Get on both sides of him!
Go around back!
There!
Maybe over here?
This Team West guy is
grabbing at random! Holy crap!
Hey, Yanagi, open your eyes!
It won't help. I forgot my glasses.
Yanagi's doing better than I thought.
President...
I'm taking you down!
The west team can dodge like the wind.
I'm pretty sure anyone could've dodged that.
Miyamura, get ready to strike back!
R-Right!
Why's Sengoku so fired up all of a sudden?
He seems to have awoken his inner general.
Huh. That makes no sense.
Look alive, Sengoku!
Yeah, yeah!
Grab him by the head!
Stare
Do you want Miyamura dead?!
The president is good at evading.
Miyamura.
Can you take it in one fell swoop?
I'm just about at my limit.
Ishikawa-kun...
I see. It's a lot more tiring
to play the horses.
What's wrong, Ishikawa?
The top of my nose really itches.
Really? Mine, too.
This is becoming a war of attrition.
Okay...
Wh-What?
President.
Who is that girl...
that's been sitting...
on your shoulder?
The...
The west team has prevailed over east!
Sengoku totally just
turned his back, didn't he?
Yeah.
Nice job, Miyamura!
Aw, man.
No big deal, I guess.
What? It's a huge deal, Hori!
Look at the score!
East
West
Come on, Remi.
We need to put these chairs back.
We were ahead until the afternoon.
It's nice that Sengoku-kun
won though, right?
But you practiced so hard for the cheer.
Not that hard.
You were the cutest one out there.
Sure, sure.
My nose got sunburned and it hurts.
Shindo's gonna make fun of me.
Huh? Hori-san?
Miyamura?
Why are you in such a hurry?
Wh-Why are you in a cheerleading outfit?
Sports day is over!
Oh, this?
The girls are taking a group picture.
I wore the boy's uniform
for the competition,
so I figured I could at least
wear this for the group photo.
You looked really good in that uniform.
Really?
I guess I'm the reason we won, then!
I'm so glad I got sunburned.
The person who's been rooting for me
since before sports day,
even long before that,
Is your face red?
I got sunburned.
is shining brighter than ever.
Am I cute?
Kidding! Just imitating Ayasaki-san.
You are cute.
Super cute, in fact.
Dummy!
You big dummy!
Today might've been
Ow...
my first and last sports day...
It was fun.
That's how I felt after it was all over.
Next time
page.4 Hori Kotatsu